Finding Aid for Joan Elizabeth Mulligan papers, 1971-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Joan Elizabeth Mulligan papers 1971-1973
Mulligan, Joan Elizabeth, 1922-
1 linear foot
85318 Aa 2
Registered nurse, and assistant professor of public health at the University of Michigan. Correspondence, notes, conference and committee records, newsclippings, and miscellaneous materials concerning abortion in Michigan; include material on abortion facilities, law reform, the Michigan Nurses Association, and anti-abortion groups.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Joan E. Mulligan (donor no. 5888 ).
The collection is open to research.
Joan E. Mulligan was a registered nurse and assistant professor of public health at the University of Michigan. She later taught at the University of Wisconsin at Madison.
The collection consists of a single series of files on the topic of abortion and abortion facilities, especially as related to issues of public health. Included are correspondence, notes, conference and committee records, newsclippings, and miscellaneous materials concerning abortion in Michigan and other states.
Subjects:
Abortion--Michigan.; Michigan Nurses Association.; Nurses--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Nursing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Public Health.; Women's rights--Michigan.
- Abortion files
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Conference on Abortion facilities, April 23-24, 1971
    - Planning meetings, February-March 1971 (Box 1)
    - Proceedings, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Conference on Abortion techniques and services, New York, June 3-5, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Conference on Public Health aspects of Abortion Law Reform, July 28, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning workshops and other meetings held in Ann Arbor, Mich., 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Notes concerning abortion (Box 1)
  - Notes for speeches given at Plymouth and Pioneer High School Ann Arbor, December 1971 and January 1972 (Box 1)
  - Notes for speech delivered before Detroit chapter of the National Organization of Women, October 18, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Nurses Association and Abortion, March 1971 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Abortion facilities in Michigan, 1971-1973
    - Membership list (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Memos, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Memos, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Agendas (Box 1)
    - "Recommended Guidelines for Abortion facilities", February 1973 (Box 1)
    - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Michigan Abortion Referendum Committee, 1972
    - Minutes Board of Directors and Executive Committee (Box 1)
    - Financial Statements (Box 1)
    - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Abortion Forum, Ann Arbor, Supreme Court on Abortion (Response by Joan E. Mulligan, representing the Michigan Nurses Association), February 1973 (Box 1)
  - Topical files
    - Michigan Clergy Counseling Service for problem pregnancies (Box 1)
    - Michigan Council for the Study of Abortion (Box 1)
    - Abortion in Michigan, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Abortion Programs in other states
      - California (Box 1)
      - Georgia (Box 1)
      - Hawaii (Box 1)
      - New York, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Washington (Box 1)
      - Wisconsin (Box 1)
    - Association for the Study of Abortion (Box 1)
    - Women's National Abortion Action Coalition (Box 1)
    - Detroit Women's Abortion Action Coalition (Box 1)
    - Preterm Institute (Washington, D.C.) (Box 1)
  - Articles on Abortion, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Anti-Abortion Literature (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Newsclippings, 3 folders (Box 1)